So we first need to create a new folder called contracts
首先我们需要创建一个名为 "contracts" 的文件夹
where we're going to store all of our contracts.
这是我们存储所有合约的地方
And let's go ahead and create a new file
我们继续，创建一个新文件
called lottery dot soul or raffle dot soul or whatever you want to call it.
可以命名为 "Lottery.sol" 或是 "Raffle.sol" 或者你想叫什么就叫什么吧
I'm going to call mine raffle dot soul.
我要命名成 "Raffle.sol"
And you might see this indexing thing happened from time to time.
你可能会看到这个 "Indexing" 什么什么的经常出现
It's our hard hat, solidity extension, indexing all of our node modules.
这是我们的 "Hardhat Solidity" 扩展正在索引所有的 "node_modules"
So it knows how to highlight things and knows how to work with everything in our solidity files.
这样它就会知道如何高亮显示和处理 Solidity 文件中的内容了
So that's what happens when that pops up.
这就是这些窗口弹出的原因
Now before we jump in and create it, let's figure out what we're going to do.
在开始动手之前，让我们先搞清楚我们到底是要做些什么
So we're going to create our raffle contract.
我们要创建一个抽奖("Raffle")合约
And what do we want people able to do?
那么我们希望人们都能够做些什么呢？
Well, we probably want people be able to enter the lottery, you know, paying some amount,
我们希望人们能够进入到彩票系统中，也就是，付一些钱
("Enter the lottery (paying some amount)")
we're probably going to want to be able to pick a random winner.
我们还希望能够，随机地选出一个优胜者
("Pick a random winner")
But we want this to be verifiably random,
但我们还希望，这是一个可以验证的随机
("verifiably random")
we want this to be untampered with a bowl.
我们希望它是不可篡改的
And we also want winner to be selected every X minutes or years or months,
我们同时还希望，每隔 X 分钟，年或月就能选出一名优胜者
("Winner to be selected every X minutes")
aka we want this to be completely automated.
也就是说，我们希望这个过程是完全自动化的
("-> completly automated")
So we want to deploy the smart contract and almost have no maintenance
所以我们希望部署的智能合约几乎不需要维护
almost have nobody ever have to touch it again.
几乎不需要有人再进行操作
And it'll just automatically run forever.
它自己就会永远自动地运行下去
This is the power of smart contracts.
这就是智能合约的力量
As we know, since we're picking a random number,
现在我们知道，我们要获取一个随机数
and we have some event driven execution,
同时我们还有一些事件驱动的执行
we know that we're going to need to use a chain link Oracle,
因此我们需要使用到 Chainlink 的预言机("Chainlink Oracle")
since we're going to need to get the randomness from outside the blockchain.
我们需要从区块链的外部来获取随机性("Randomness")
And we're going to need to have that automated execution.
并且，我们还需要它能自动执行("Automated Execution")
Because a smart contract can execute itself, we need somebody to automatically trigger these.
因为智能合约无法自行启动，我们需要有人来自动触发它们
So to trigger selecting a winner, we're gonna have to use the chain link keepers.
因此，为了触发遴选优胜者，我们需要使用 "Chainlink Keepers"
And that's pretty much going to be our entire code.
这几乎就是我们全部的代码了
Now, I usually like to do this before I start any project.
通常，在开启任何项目之前我都喜欢进行这样的处理
And the reason that I do a little bit of brainstorming is because we don't want to just jump in and really do anything,
之所以要进行这样的思考是因为我不希望我们盲目地开工
we want to have a good idea of what we're trying to build
我希望我们对所要构建的内容能有一个清晰的设想
so that we can write tests for it,
这样我们才能编写相应的测试
so that we can know if we're going in the right direction, etc.
这样我们才能知道我们是否走在正确的方向上
Now that we have a good idea of where we're going, let's build it.
现在我们已经有了一个清晰的构想了，让我们开始构建它吧
So per usual, let's do spdx license identifier. And my team
通常，我们会先写一句 `SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT`
will do pragma solidity little caret here, zero point 8.7,
然后是 `pragma solidity ^0.8.7;`
even zoom out, just a hair will trash that
视图稍微缩小一点，把这个删掉
and we'll say contract, raffle,
接着是 `contract Raffle {}`
we can even make sure that we're not going crazy
我们甚至可以这样做，来确保不要出问题
by doing a little yarn Hardhead compile and compiled successfully,
`yarn hardhat compile`，编译成功
we want it to be able to enter the lottery want us to be able to enter it.
我们希望能够进入到彩票系统中("Enter the lottery")，能够参与其中
So maybe we'll create a function called enter raffle.
所以我们可能要创建一个 `function enterRaffle(){}`
What else do we want to do, we want to be able to pick a random winner.
我们还要做些什么？我们希望能够选出一个随机的优胜者
So maybe we'll create a function called pick a random winner, and boom.
所以我们可能需要创建一个 `function pickRandomWinner() {}`，好了
So let's comment out pick random winner for now.
现在，让我们先注释掉 "pickRandomWinner"
And let's just work on this enter raffle thing.
先来处理一下这个 "enterRaffle"
In the past, we've created projects like Funmi,
过去，在我们创建类似 "FundMe" 这样的项目时
where people can send ether to our contracts or send whatever native blockchain token to our smart contracts
人们可以使用基于美元价值的 "message.value"
using the message dot value based off of some USD value.
向我们的合约发送以太币或是其它区块链原生代币
For this one, we're just going to have the entrance fee instead be USD based,
但这次，我们打算直接使用入场费而不是美元
it's just going to be that native asset.
它将直接成为原生资产
So for our enter raffle, we don't have to set a USD price,
所以对于我们的 "enterRaffle"，我们不再设置美元价格
we can just set a minimum eath price.
而是直接设置最低以太币价格
So up at the top, let's pick our minimum price.
来到顶部，让我们来设置一下最低价格
So we'll do a un 256 entrance fee.
`uint256 entranceFee;`
And now some of our learnings from our last section should come in here,
现在，就要用到我们在上一节中学到的某些东西了
we now know that this entrance fee is going to be a what, it's going to be a storage variable.
我们现在已经知道这个 "entranceFee" 是什么东西了，它是一个 storage 变量
So let's prepend it with s underscore let's make a private variable
让我们在它前面加上 "s_" 将其设置为一个 "private" 变量
because we always want to set our visibility.
因为我们总是希望明确指定可见性("visibility")
But let's have the entrance fee be configurable.
但是我们要把它设置为可配置的
Well, let's create a constructor now.
好了，让我们现在开始创建构造函数吧 `constructor()`
And we'll have this entrance fee be settable in our constructor,
并且，我们要让 "entranceFee" 在构造函数中是可设置的
so our constructor will take a UNT two to the sixth entrance fee,
因此我们的构造函数要接收一个 `uint256 entranceFee`
s underscore entrance fee equals entrance fee.
`s_entranceFee = entranceFee`
Well, if we're gonna only set this one time, we might as well make this a constant or an immutable variable.
嗯，如果我们只设置它一次，那么我们将其创建为一个 "constant" 或者 "immutable" 变量可能会更好
So let's make this an immutable variable so that we save some gas
我们来把它设置成一个 "immutable" 变量，这样可以节省一些 gas
we'll change this from S to I and now we're saying
我们要把 "s" 变成 "i"，现在我们说的就是
you interviewed six private immutable I entrance fee equals entrance fee.
"uint256 private immutable i_entranceFee = entranceFee"
Now we probably are going to want other users to see the entrance fee.
我们可能还想要其他用户也可以看到这个 "entranceFee"
So down below, we can create function get entrance fee,
所以划到下面，创建 `function getEntranceFee()`
and this will be a public view function which will returns a UN to the set Next,
它是一个 `public view` 函数，返回一个 `uint256`
and we'll just say return entrance fee.
然后我们直接写 `return entranceFee`
Now we have a function that users can call to get the entrance fee.
现在我们就有了一个函数，可以让用户调取 "entranceFee" 了
But we, as developers can use this AI entrance fee to know this is an immutable variable.
但我们作为开发者，可以直接使用这个 "i_entranceFee" 并且知道它是一个 "immutable" 变量
This is pretty cheap gas wise for us to read from
这样我们读取时花费的 gas 就会相当便宜
in our enter raffle, we've done a ton of these before,
在我们的 "enterRaffle" 中，我们之前已经做过不少类似的工作了
all we need to do
所有我们需要做的事就是
is we just need to require the message dot value is greater than that I underscore entrance fee,
限制 `msg.value` 要大于 "i_entranceFee"
("require msg.value > i_entranceFee")
what we've learned before about those error codes,
但我们之前学过一些关于错误代码的知识
so we could use require message dot value, or we could do one of these customers,
我们可以使用 "require msg.value" 也可以创建一个自定义错误类型
which is going to be a lot more gas efficient,
它具有更高的 gas 使用效率
because instead of storing this string,
因为它不再是存储一段字符串
we're just going to store an error code in our smart contract.
而是把错误代码直接存储在了我们的智能合约中
So let's do that. Instead,
所以让我们来替换一下吧
we'll say if the message dot value is less than our eye entrance fee,
`if(msg.value < i_entranceFee)`
(如果 "msg.value" 小于 "i_entranceFee")
then we're just going to revert the whole transaction with some error code.
就使用某些错误代码回滚整个交易 (``)
And we'll use a best practice naming raffle underscore underscore not enough eath entered.
接着我们使用主流的写法 `Raffle__NotEnoughETHEntered();`
And we'll grab this arrow code.
我们获取这段错误代码
And we'll have if the user doesn't send enough value
接着，如果用户没有发送足够的价值
will revert with not enough eath entered
就执行 ``
now that we know they're calling into raffle with enough value,
现在，既然我们已经知道他们使用了足够的价值调用 "enterRaffle" 了
we're probably going to want to keep track of all the users who actually enter our raffle.
那么我们可能就要持续追踪所有成功进入抽奖的用户了
That way, when we pick a winner, we know who's in the running.
这样，我们才能在选出优胜者的时候，搞清楚都有谁在参与竞争
So let's create an array of players at the top
所以我们要在顶部创建一个玩家("players")数组
error here.
这里还有个 `error`
And then just to make this look even nicer, we'll do a little comment here.
还有，为了能让这里更好看一些，我们可以在这里做一些注释
And we'll say state variables.
我们就说，状态变量 (`/* State Variables */`)
And we'll combine both our storage and are not storage variables just in this state variable section.
我们将把我们的 storage 变量和非 storage 变量都存放在这个 "State Variables" 部分里
So we'll do address array players.
接着我们写 `address[] players`
Now players, of course, is going to have to be in storage,
当然了，"players" 必须要存放在 storage 里
because we're going to modify this a lot, we're going to be adding and subtracting players all the time.
因为我们要经常对其进行修改，会一直增加和移除玩家
So we're going to do s players will make this private as well.
我们把这个也改成私有的 `private s_players`
And we're going to make this address payable players
同时我们要让这些地址是 `payable` 的
because one of these players wins, we're going to need to have to pay them.
因为最终会有一位玩家胜出，我们需要把钱支付给他们
So we'll make this address payable private as players.
所以我们要这么创建 `address payable[] private s_players`
And since we're going to make this private,
由于我们把它变成私有的了
and it's probably good that we know who's in the players array,
所以我们需要知道都有谁在这个 "players" 数组里
we'll even do function it player. This will be a public view
我们可以这样做 `function getPlayer()` 它也是 `public view` 的
that returns an address of one of these players.
然后返回一个玩家的地址 `returns(address)`
And we'll just return s players of index
接着我们直接返回 `return s_players[index]`
will have this function, take a un 256 index as an input parameter,
我们要让这个函数，接收一个 `uint256 index` 作为输入参数
we know that players is going to be a storage variable.
我们知道 "players" 是一个 storage 变量
And we're going to add it to our enter raffle
并且我们会把它添加进我们的 "enterRaffle" 里
Oh, and we definitely want our Inter raffle to be public and to be payable.
哦！我们肯定是要让 "enterRaffle" 是 `public` 以及 `payable` 的
Since we're having people send message dot value, and we want anyone to be able to enter our raffle.
因为我们需要人们发送 "msg.value"，并且我们还需要他们能够进入到我们的抽奖中来
So it'll be public, it'll be payable, it'll be perfect.
所以它是 "public" 的，也是 "payable" 的，非常完美
Now that we have our array, and someone's entered the raffle,
现在我们有了这个数组，并且某个人已经进入到抽奖中了
we'll do s players dot push message dot sender.
我们执行 `s_players.push(msg.sender);`
Now, this doesn't actually work because message dot sender isn't a payable address.
目前，它还无法实际运行，因为 "msg.sender" 还不是一个 `payable` 的地址
So we'll need to typecast it as a payable address
所以我们需要做一个类型转换，把它变成一个 "payable" 的地址
just by wrapping it in payable.
直接放进 `payable()` 里就行了
So now we have a way to keep track of all the players that are entering a raffle.
现在我们已经成功追踪到所有进入到抽奖中的玩家了